<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0"  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="dist-examples">
  <title>vFabric GemFire Programming Examples Documentation</title>

  <para>Complete the installation procedure for each physical or VMware virtual machine on which you will run the vFabric GemFire examples.</para>

  <para>GemFire includes an evaluation license that enables you to run the examples and perform simple evaluation activities. This license allows you to run up to three peer or cache server members and up to three clients for each cache server member. GemFire uses the default license whenever it is run without other valid licensing. This license never expires. It is not allowed for production use.
.</para>

  <para>The sample is bundled with the distribution and is Maven or gradle-based. One
  can easily import them into any Maven-aware IDE (such as SpringSource <ulink
  url="http://www.springsource.com/products/sts">Tool Suite</ulink>) or run
  them from the command-line.</para>

  <section id="setup-examples:prerequisites">
    <title>Prerequisites</title>

    <para>Install GemFire as described in Install vFabric GemFire.</para>

    <section id="setup-examples:procedure">
      <title>Procedure</title>
    </section>
    <section id="setup-examples:what-to-do-next">
      <title>What to do next</title>
    </section>


 <table border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="12" width="650" >
  <tr>
   <td valign="top" width="24%"><a href="EnvSetup.html">Environment Settings</a> </td>
   <td valign="top">
		A guide to setting up your environment to run the examples. 
		<hr color="#330066" width="75%" size="1" align="left"> </hr>
   	</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td valign="top" width="24%">Examples</td>
   <td valign="top"> 
   		Sample GemFire Java applications:
   	<ul>
        <li><b><a href="dist/cacheOverflow/README.html">cacheOverflow</a></b>: 
            a program that demonstrates how the logical amount of data
            stored in a GemFire cache region can exceed the amount of
            heap space in a Java Virtual Machine.</li>
        <li><b><a href="dist/cacheRunner/README.html">cacheRunner</a></b>: 
            a program that loads a cache.xml file and interactively runs caching commands.</li>
        <li><a href="dist/clientAPI/README.html"><strong>clientAPI</strong></a>:  shows client configuration through the API for a producer client and a consumer client. </li>
        <li><b><a href="dist/clientServerConfigs/README.html">clientServerConfigs</a></b>: 
            provides configuration files for creating a client/server caching system. This example also demonstrates GemFire authentication and authorization.</li>
        <li><b><a href="dist/flashcache/README.html">flashcache</a></b>: a program 
            that retrieves and caches stock quotes.</li>
        <li><b><a href="dist/haOverflow/README.html">haOverflow</a></b>: demonstrates HA queue overflow for durable clients.        </li>
        <li><b><a href="dist/healthMonitor/README.html">healthMonitor</a></b>: 
            a JMX client application that connects to a GemFire 
            JMX Agent via the RMIConnector defined in JSR 160 to monitor the health 
            of a GemFire distributed system.</li>
        <li><b><a href="dist/systemExplorer/README.html">systemExplorer</a></b>: 
            a command-line application for exercising GemFire's 
            com.gemstone.gemfire.admin API.</li>
        <LI><B><A HREF="DIST/WAN/README.HTML">WAN</A></B>:
            AN APPLICATION THAT SIMULATES TWO WAN SITES.</LI>
        <li><b><a href="dist/delta/README.html">delta</a></b>:
            an application that demonstrates delta propagation.</li>
        <li><b><a href="dist/transaction/README.html">transaction</a></b>:
            an application that demonstrates how to use transactions with colocated partitioned regions.</li>
        <li><b><a href="dist/portableDataExchange/README.html">portableDataExchange</a></b>: 
            an application that demonstrates how to serialize objects using the Portable Data eXchange framework.</li>
        <li><b><a href="dist/partitionedPersistence/README.html">partitionedPersistence</a></b>: 
            an application that demonstrates how to use partitioned regions with disk persistence.</li>
     </ul>
		<hr color="#330066" width="75%" size="1" align="left"></hr>
   	</td>
  </tr>

 </table>
  </section>
</chapter>
